shillingtoneducation.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy notice – Shillington Education

## Website Privacy Notice of the Shillington Group

_Updated: 24 May 2018_

The Shillington Group is comprised of

**Shillington College Limited** (Registered in England and Wales Company No 06220665)  whose registered office is Kirkleas, Old Road, Buckland, Surrey RH3 7DZ  
**Shillington School of Graphic Design LLC** (registered in Delaware, whose place of business is 315, Madison Avenue, New York 10017, U.S.A.  
**Kandilli Holdings Pty, trading as Shillington College** (ABN 81003352681) whose place of business is 50, Margaret Street, Sydney, NSW 2000, Australia)

Referred to together as “The Group”

The Group Data Compliance Officer can be contacted at [ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com](mailto:ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com)

This privacy notice is in three parts.

**Part 1** (for Clients): With the introduction the EU General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR), which become effective in law on 25th May 2018 and new Data Protection Laws to replace the Data Protection Act 1998 (together “Data Protection Legislation”), we are required to update the data protection references in our terms of business and, in the case of individual clients, provide certain details regarding the Group and collection and use of your personal data. This is set out in more detail below.

**Part 2** (for all Visitors): The second part sets out, in relation to information we collect from this Site, the practices we follow to respect the privacy of all visitors.

**Part 3** : Other Applicable Information

## Part 1

If at any point you believe the information we process on you is incorrect you can request to see this information and even have it corrected or deleted. If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data, you can contact our Group Compliance Officer who will investigate the matter.

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are processing your personal data not in accordance with the law you can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).

Unless otherwise agreed with you, we will only collect basic personal data about you. We may also need to hold ‘sensitive personal data’ in order for us to be able to deliver our services to you in as effective a manner as possible. Basic personal data includes your name, and contact details including work address, email address and job title. Sensitive information includes a number of types of data relating to race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or other similar beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health, sexual life, or criminal record.

We will only hold “sensitive personal data” if you enrol for one of our courses and we will seek your consent to do so as part of the enrolment process.

A full list of your rights under the Data Protection Legislation is as follows:

  1. The right to access the personal data we hold on you
  2. The right to correct and update the personal data we hold on you
  3. The right to have your personal data erased
  4. The right to object to processing of your personal data
  5. The right to data portability
  6. The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time for any processing of personal data to which consent was sought.
  7. The right to object to the processing of personal data where applicable.
  8. The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office. You can [contact the Information Commissioners Office via email](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/), on 0303 123 1113,  or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire SK9 5AF.

We need to know basic personal data in order to provide you with our services, and to claim our right to be paid in return for our services, under our standard terms of business. If you do not provide this information then we will be unable to provide the services you have requested. We will not collect any personal data from you that we do not need in order to provide and oversee the services we have agreed to provide to you.

All the personal data we hold about you will be processed by Group staff  and no third parties will have access to your personal data unless there is a legal obligation for us to provide them with this.  We have set out below the legal bases for The Group to process your data.

Some of our processing may be necessary for compliance with a legal obligation. For example the Group may have duties to act as a data controller and may be obliged to report certain matters to law enforcement agencies and/or educational regulatory bodies. The Group ensures that internal compliance is in full accordance with the requirements of theData Protection Legislation.

Some of our processing is necessary to comply with our contractual obligations to clients and prospective clients. It is necessary in order to provide our graphic design services to our clients

We will also communicate with you, as a matter of legitimate interest,  information about other services we can offer you and update you about our activities.

Where your information is used other than in accordance with one of these uses, we will first obtain your consent to that use.

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is processed securely and more information on this can be found on our website.

We will generally keep your personal data for a maximum of 6 years, after which time it will be destroyed if it is no longer required for the lawful purpose(s) for which it was obtained. In the United States and Australia we may be required to hold your personal data for at least 20 years. If you consent to marketing, any information we use for this purpose will be kept with us until you notify us that you no longer wish to receive this information.

Your personal data will only be shared with third parties including other data controllers where it is necessary for the performance of the data controllers’ tasks or where you first give us your prior consent. It is likely that we will need to share your data with:

  * Our agents, suppliers and contractors. For example, we may ask a supplier to send out newsletters on our behalf, or to maintain our database software, or to provide us with administration, IT and other related services;

## Part 2

At The Group we implement fair information practices that are designed to protect your privacy. If you have questions or you do not feel that your concerns have been addressed in our privacy statement, or you just want to talk with us, feel free to contact us by email to [ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com](mailto:ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com)

We collect personally identifiable information that is voluntarily provided by visitors to this Site (User Data). The User Data that The Group receives from Site visitors includes name, title, address, email address, screen name, telephone and fax numbers, and any other information provided by visitors in email messages or attachments thereto

Typically, User Data is collected in order to assist visitors to enrol on a course or to express interest in our services

It is The Group’s policy to limit the information collected to only the minimum information required to complete a Site visitor’s request.

The Group’s intention is not to seek any sensitive information through our Site unless legally required for enrolment purposes as set out in Part 1, insurance or recruitment purposes. Sensitive information includes a number of types of data relating to race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or other similar beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health, sexual life, or criminal record.

User Data obtained by the Site is used for internal business purposes of the Group and in connection with a visitor’s request. This data is not shared with others for unrelated purposes unless stated in this Privacy Policy or otherwise communicated to the Site visitor.

The Group makes every practical effort to avoid excessive or irrelevant collection of data. If a visitor believes the Site has collected excessive information, we encourage the visitor to contact [ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com](mailto:ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com) to raise any concerns.

Except for instances where visitors explicitly choose to receive specific The Group marketing or other informational materials The Group will not use personal data collected from our Website to distribute marketing or informational materials.

## Part 3

It is the Group’s policy to process all data including User Data in accordance with GDPR principles and Data Protection Legislation and only to disclose User Data to third parties who ask us to provide services to them. Otherwise, unless required by law to do so, we do not share User Data with third parties.

We do share User Data:

  * when explicitly [requested](http://www.apple.com/) by the visitor
  * when required to deliver publications or reference materials requested by the visitor
  * when required to facilitate conferences or events hosted by a third party
  * when required to meet any other request of a visitor.
  * When there is a legal obligation to do so.

Categories of third parties with whom we may share personally identifiable information include National Governments and Educational Regulatory bodies in the United States of America and Australia. This Site does not collect or compile personally identifying information for dissemination or sale to outside parties for consumer marketing purposes, or host mailings on behalf of third parties.

## Cookie Policy

A cookie is a tiny element of data that a website can send to a visitor’s computer’s browser so that this computer will be recognised by the site on their return. Cookies allow our web server to recognise a computer on connection to the Site, which in turn allows the server to make downloading of pages faster than on first viewing. In addition, cookies may also be used by us to establish statistics about the use of the Site by Internet users by gathering and analysing data such as: most visited pages, time spent by users on each page, site performance, etc. By collecting and using such data, we hope to improve the quality of the Site. 

The data collected by our servers and/or through cookies that may be placed on your computer will not be kept for longer than is necessary to fulfil the purposes set out in our Privacy Notice. In any event, such information may not be kept for longer than one year.

Navigation data about site viewers is automatically collected by our servers. If you do not wish to have this navigation data collected, we recommend that you do not use the Site. A visitor can also set their browser to block the recording of cookies on their hard drive to minimise the amount of data that may be collected about your navigating on the Site. The browser on a computer can be set to notify the user when a cookie is being recorded on their computer’s hard drive. Most browsers can also be set to keep cookies from being recorded on their computer. However, for optimal use of the Site, we recommend that visitors do not block the recording of cookies on their computer.

All The Group servers and computer systems are protected from outside intrusions. As a result, all data that may be collected about Site viewers through the use of cookies will be protected from unauthorised access.

We may at some stage use cookies to identify users when they visit the Site to use personalised services. In such circumstances these cookies may be kept on the hard drive of their computer following closure of the web browser. Cookies used in connection with such services enable us to build up a profile of our users and to develop personalised versions of the Site.

For more information about cookies, please see the Information Commissioner’s website home page or the Interactive Advertising Bureau.

A visitor may choose to not receive a cookie file by enabling your web browser to refuse cookies. The procedure for refusal of cookies may vary for different software products. Please check with your internet browser software help or your software supplier if you wish to refuse cookies.

The Internet is a global environment. In order to provide the Site we may need to transfer User Data to locations outside the jurisdiction in which a visitor is viewing the Site (the User Jurisdiction) and process User Data outside the User Jurisdiction. If the User Jurisdiction is within the European Economic Area (the EEA) please note that such transfers and processing of personal data may be in locations outside the EEA. Any data sent or uploaded by users may be accessible in jurisdictions outside the User Jurisdiction (including outside the EEA). The level of data protection offered in such jurisdictions may be less than that offered within the User Jurisdiction or (as the case may be) within the EEA, although we will seek to ensure that where information is so transferred by The Group we will comply with the relevant legal rules governing such transfers.

By continuing to use the Site and by providing any personal data (including sensitive personal data) to us via the Site or email addresses provided on the Site, visitors are consenting to such transfers, provided that they are in accordance with the purposes set out above and elsewhere in the Privacy Policy. Please do not send us any personal data if you do not consent to the transfer of this information to locations outside the User Jurisdiction (including, if applicable, outside the EEA)

As a policy, visitors are not required to register to gain access to this Site. Personally identifiable information provided to The Group through this Site is provided voluntarily by visitors. Should visitors subsequently choose to unsubscribe from mailing lists or any registrations, we will provide instructions on the appropriate Website area or in communications to our visitors; or a visitor may contact [ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com](mailto:ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com)

Each visitor has the right of access to personal data they have submitted through this Site.

Enquiries about the accuracy of identifying information previously submitted, or requests to have information removed, should be directed to [ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com](mailto:ukfinance@shillingtoneducation.com)

All The Group staff are instructed to follow a firm-wide security policy. Only authorised personnel are provided access to personally-identifiable information and these employees are required to agree to ensure confidentiality of this information.

The Group reserves the right to modify or amend this statement at any time. The effective date will be displayed at the beginning of this statement. To keep visitors informed The Group will notify users of material changes to our Privacy Statement by prominently identifying a link on our website home page to the updated Privacy Policy for a period of not less than two weeks.

By continuing to use the Site and by providing any personal data (including sensitive personal data) to us via the Site or email addresses provided on the Site, visitors are consenting to our use of your personal data as set out in this Privacy Policy. Please do not send us any personal data if you do not want that information to be used by us in this manner.

All documents, programmes, publications, designs, products, processes, software, technology, information, and ideas (Content) provided by or described in this Site are the property of The Group and are protected by U.K. and international copyright laws and other intellectual property laws, unless stated otherwise. The Content is provided to users of this Site for informational purposes only. Except as expressly permitted below or by applicable law, users may not copy (except to the extent required in order to use the site in accordance with the Legal Notice), store in any medium (including in any other website), distribute, transmit, re-transmit, broadcast, modify, or otherwise make available or communicate to the public any part of the Site or systematically extract material from the Site or any document available through it or in any other way exploit commercially all or any part of the Site or any document available through it without our prior written permission.

Users may print or save one copy of any page of the Site and documents available through it (other than documents provided by third parties) for their own personal use.

Campus and Intake Date

### How it works

Ready to apply for Shillington's graphic design course? You're four steps away. Simply select your campus and course, share your personal details, pay the initial deposit and we'll get in touch to confirm all the details. 

Still researching? Learn more about our course and view course dates and fees. 

Find available courses
